Willis A. Tingey papers, 1960-1994
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Willis A. Tingey papers, 1960-1994
AZ 558
Tingey, Willis A.
Contains mainly documents created by Willis A. Tingey related to land management, area development and irrigation on the Navajo and Hopi Indian reservations, Arizona and New Mexico, 1960-1994.
3 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Land surveyor and civil engineer.
Scope and Content Note
Contains mainly documents created by Willis A. Tingey related to land management, area development and irrigation on the Navajo and Hopi Indian reservations, Arizona and New Mexico, 1960-1994.
Access Terms
Tingey, Willis A.
Navajo Indians -- Agriculture
Hopi Indians -- Agriculture
Irrigation -- Utah
Irrigation -- Arizona
Irrigation -- New Mexico
Indians of North America -- Agriculture
Correspondence
Container List
- Correspondence. May-July, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Correspondence between Tingey and Gary Rydout, Librarian at the Western Archeological and Conservation Center, related to the acquisition of the collection and containing Tingey's extensive comments on the origin and significance of the documents.
- Monograph, An Approach to Engineering Problems: a Preliminary Title Listing on Reconnaissance Model Study Plans for a Manuscript Series on Full Area Development. 1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Monograph, Preliminary Report on Small Irrigation Systems on Chinle Wash, Navajo Indian Reservation, Arizona. copy 6 [photocopy]. 1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Monograph, A Technical Manual: Reconnaissance Study Plan Procedures. An Introduction to a Glossary of Planning Terms and Science and the Environment. 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Monograph, Navajo-Hopi Indian Reservations: an Atlas of Maps. copy 3. 1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Monograph, The Development of a Master Plan for Pueblo Colorado Wash Drainage Basin: The Introduction of a Schematic Model Base Study Plan. pt. 1 & pt. 2 (maps). 1977 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Monograph, Navajo-Hopi Indian Reservations: an Atlas of Maps. 1980 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Monograph, Modern Methods in Irrigation: Workshop Manual. Student Edition. copy 10. 1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Monograph, A Revised Correlated Study Plan: Water Land Resource Development for the Approaches to Flat Bottom Terrace, East Brigham City, Box Elder County, Utah. (not complete). 1980. 1980 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Monograph, Area (Land) Inventory Study: U.S. Public Lands Surveys and Resurveys, Section 36 and Vicinity, T12N R1E Salt Lake Meridian. 1983 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Monograph, A Reconnaissance Study Layout Plan: Commercial Drip and Gravity Flow Low Pressure Irrigation Systems, Many Farms Cooperative Farm Project, Many Farms, Arizona, and a Garden Irrigation Development Unit, Logan, Utah. copy 5. 1983 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Monograph, The Use of Standard Topographical Maps and Photography in the Development of Route Surveys and Area Study Plans. 1983 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Monograph, Illustrative Models on Residential Buildings for Subdivisions and Support Services Thereto. copy 5. 1984 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Monograph, A Reconnaissance Model Study Plan for a Manuscript Series on Full Area Development: an Index to Items Therein Contained. copy 4. 1984 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Monograph, Detailed Item Inventory: Reconnaissance Plan. General Dam Site, with Appurtenances Thereto. Nipple Lake Reconnaissance Irrigation Development Plan, Paria River Drainage Basin, Kane County, Utah. 1986 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Monograph, A Geographical Dictionary on Cities, Towns, Villages, etc. in or Adjacent to Navajo-Hopi Indian Reservations in Arizona- New Mexico-Utah. 1986 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Monograph, An Introduction to a Reconnaissance Master Plan on Elements in an Irrigation Study Plan on Full Development for Paria River Drainage Basin in Kane-Garfield Counties, Utah (A Part of Upper Paria River Valley). copy 9. 1986 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Monograph, A Reconnaissance Study Plan on Full Development of a Resource Area: South Paria, Utah to Junct. Upper Paria Valley with Cottonwood Creek and Vicinity (an example). 1986 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Monograph, Navajo Farming, by Sam and Janet Bingham. Logan, Utah: Utah State University, 1979. Inscribed by authors. 1979 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Map Index to published standard topographical maps in or adjacent to the eastern Navajo Division Navajo Indian reservation, New Mexico; Arizona Division, Navajo/Hopi Indian reservations; Utah Division, Navajo Indian reservation. No Date (Box 6, Folder 1)
- An atlas of modern standard topographical maps. Total area coverage at the map scale 1/24,000 or 1/62,500 and total area coverage at map scale of 1/100,00. The exhibit has not been assembled as part of the report. No Date (Box 6, Folder 2)
- A geographical dictionary on cities, towns, vil-lages, etc. in or adjacent to Navajo/Hopi Indian reservations in Arizona, New Mexico, and Utah. No Date (Box 6, Folder 3)
- A gazetteer on cities, towns, villages, etc., in or adjacent to east section, eastern Navajo division, Navajo Indian reservations and vicinity, New Mexico. No Date (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Appendages to geographical dictionary on cities, towns, villages, etc. in or adjacent to Navajo/Hopi Indian reservations, 1952-62. 1986 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- An atlas of maps prepared by the Bureau of Indian Affairs on small (misc.) irrigation projects lo-cated in the Navajo/Hopi Indian reservations, Arizona and New Mexico, 1956. 1987 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Navajo Project, Hogback Unit, New Mexico. Comple-tion report, December 1962 by Vernon J. Larson. Assembled as an appendage to a geographical dic-tionary on cities, towns, villages, etc., in or adjacent to Navajo/Hopi Indian reservations in Arizona, New Mexico, Utah, Colorado. 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Reconnaissance Model Study Plans. Procedures for Full Area Development of Pueblo Colorado Wash Basin: Pueblo Colorado Wash, Steamboat Wash-East Fork Wash, Steamboat Canyon East. Navajo-Hopi Indian Reservations, Arizona: Introduction to existing condition today. No Date (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Reconnaissance Model Study Plans. Procedures for Full Area Development of Pueblo Colorado Wash Basin: Pueblo Colorado Wash, Steamboat Wash-East Fork Wash, Steamboat Canyon East. Navajo-Hopi Indian Reservations, Arizona: Primary text. Full area development: General plan. Geographical dictionary. No Date (Box 7, Folder 2-3)
- Reconnaissance Model Study Plans. Procedures for Full Area Development of Pueblo Colorado Wash Basin: Pueblo Colorado Wash, Steamboat Wash-East Fork Wash, Steamboat Canyon East. Navajo-Hopi Indian Reservations, Arizona: Support plans: Recon plans-Profiles-Grades. No Date (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Reconnaissance Model Study Plans. Procedures for Full Area Development of Pueblo Colorado Wash Basin: Pueblo Colorado Wash, Steamboat Wash-East Fork Wash, Steamboat Canyon East. Navajo-Hopi Indian Reservations, Arizona: Support plans: Recon plans-Profiles-Grades. No Date (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
- Reconnaissance Model Study Plans. Procedures for Full Area Development of Pueblo Colorado Wash Basin: Pueblo Colorado Wash, Steamboat Wash-East Fork Wash, Steamboat Canyon East. Navajo-Hopi Indian Reservations, Arizona: Enlarged details. Structures and sites. No Date (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Reconnaissance Model Study Plans. Procedures for Full Area Development of Pueblo Colorado Wash Basin: Pueblo Colorado Wash, Steamboat Wash-East Fork Wash, Steamboat Canyon East. Navajo-Hopi Indian Reservations, Arizona: Steamboat Canyon East. No Date (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Reconnaissance Model Study Plans. Procedures for Full Area Development of Pueblo Colorado Wash Basin: Pueblo Colorado Wash, Steamboat Wash-East Fork Wash, Steamboat Canyon East. Navajo-Hopi Indian Reservations, Arizona: Separates. No Date (Box 9, Folder 3-4)
- Reconnaissance Model Study Plans. Procedures for Full Area Development of Pueblo Colorado Wash Basin: Pueblo Colorado Wash, Steamboat Wash-East Fork Wash, Steamboat Canyon East. Navajo-Hopi Indian Reservations, Arizona: Appendages. No Date (Box 9, Folder 5)